SK. NAEEM FERDOUS

295/A/1 Tali Office Rd., Hazaribagh, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Primary Mobile No: 01944633028 Email: naeemferdous@gmail.com



Career Objective:

To work in an environment where there is an opportunity of self-assessment and self-improvement in both individual and group based work that will ultimately lead to the further development of the common people and organization.

Career Summary:

Human Resources Generalist with progressive experience managing employee benefits & compliance, employee hiring & on boarding, performance management processes and HR records. Dependable and organized team player with the ability to communicate effectively and efficiently. Skilled at building relationships with employees across all levels of an organization. Proficient with HRIS, applicant tracking and benefits management.

Employment History:

1. Asst. Manager, Operations & Supplies

(November, 2016 - Continuing)

FedEx Bangladesh (Sister concern of MGH group)

Area of Expertise

Administration & Supply chain management

Duties/Responsibilities

- 1. Check & process all **operational expenses** & vouchers from branch offices.
- 2. Compile & analyse the monthly data for pick-ups and deliveries of shipments of branches.
- 3. Managing employee incentives of branch offices.
- 4. Follow up the proper functions of operational.
- 5. Ensure operational & logistic support for branch offices.
- 6. Regularly review inventory status.
- 7. Escalate & follow up the out-of-delivery areas shipments for the concerned branches.
- 8. Ensuring local purchase from contract vendor and follow up goods receipts.
- 9. Ensure continual improvement of work process and of self-development.
- 10. Monitoring and controlling the store at optimum level and supervise receiving, storing, and issuing of goods.
- 11. Analyse branch-wise shipments data to predict sales & **procure logistics supplies** for local & abroad.
- 12. Communicate & Follow up with shipping agent, C&F agent and Transport company for **FedEx supplies processing for port/air & clearance.**
- 13. Carry out any other responsibilities as advised by the supervisor from time to time.

2. Assistant Manager, Admin & HR

(November, 2013 - October, 2016)

T. K. group of Industries

Area of Expertise

Compensation/ Benefits/ Attendance/ Leave Management, Factory HR Administration, HRIS/ HR Database Management

Duties/Responsibilities

- 1. Administrate employee by Labour Law 2006 & Company Policy.
- 2. Counselling for employees Health, Safety issues.
- 3. Maintain Leave of employees.
- 4. **Prepare monthly salaries** of regular employees & daily employees.
- 5. Deal with **Recruitment Process**.
- 6. Handling Disciplinary & Grievance issues.
- 7. Prepare EL Encashment and Final settlement.
- 8. Renewal of **Factory Licenses, Environmental Licenses, Trade Licenses** & Practical "C class" license from the Governmental Departments.

3. Human Resources Officer

(August, 2010 - October, 2013)

Singer Bangladesh Ltd.

Area of Expertise

Administrative, General HR

Duties/Responsibilities

- 1. Maintain & update employee database. Ensure monthly update in organogram.
- 2. Employees leave record maintenance and attendance follow. Ensure employees on time confirmation and contract agreements.
- 3. Should take care of joining formalities and exit formalities.
- 4. Support the Head of Human Resources in Recruitment and Selection.
- 5. Cooperate in conducting training programs and arranging annual programs e.g. Picnic, etc.
- 6. Communicate **employee complains, grievances, suggestions, demands** etc. to top management, especially the Head of Human Resources.
- 7. Ensure proper and timely functioning and maintenance of Transport facility for the employees
- 8. Supervise the duties of canteen assistant and cleaning staff
- 9. Generating and Cross checking of various reports e.g. over-time reports, casual payment statement, Yearly manpower reports etc.
- 10. Incorporating best HR practice in line with Singer HR policy.
- 11. Disciplining employees in accordance with the organizational policy & Guidelines and Labour Law 2006.
- 12. Allocate human resources, ensuring appropriate matches between personnel.
- 13. Plan and **conduct new employee orientation** to foster positive attitude toward organizational objectives.
- 14. Managing employee appraisal process and procedures.
- 15. Renewal of Factory Licenses, Environmental Licenses, Explosive Licenses, Trade Licenses from the Governmental Departments.

4. Capacity Building Specialist (contractual)

(July, 2008 - July, 2010)

Stromme Foundation- Regional Office, Asia.

Area of Expertise

Manual Development/ Documentation, Monitoring, Research

Duties/Responsibilities

- 1. Help Partner organizations in Developing field level action plans for Partner Business Plan Development
- 2. Internal audit and control, risk management (operational, credit, market and business)

- 3. Portfolio management, including growth strategies, work-outs etc.
- 4. Overall management of the office set-up and general administration of the project office;
- 5. Provide logistic support to international and local consultants of the project;
- 6. Process and do whatever is required to get the visas extension of the international staff
- 7. Assist in obtaining security clearance, claiming tax exemption, opening bank accounts etc. for the international consultants;
- 8. Collect and deliver documents, information from Government office, Project office to Head office and vice-versa;
- 9. Provide all logistic support for any workshops, seminars, conferences;
- 10. Supervise the work of support and service staff;
- 11. Manage and maintain vehicle fleet, project vehicles;
- 12. Check that the requisitions for purchase of stationary, supplies, books, printing, spiral binding, laminating of documents etc. are maintained properly;
- 13. Initiate, coordinate and supervise the procurement of goods and services as per plan;
- 14. Maintain proper documentation and filing of goods and services as per plan;

5. Trainer, Micro Finance and Enterprise Training Unit

(June, 2003 - June, 2008)

BRAC, head office.

Area of Expertise

Recruitment & Selection, Training & Development

Duties/Responsibilities

- 1.To develop and design new, innovative products for Micro Finance Program of BRAC and other potential customers.
- 2.To conduct trainings on Financial Management and Micro Finance Management and Small Business Analysis course for Micro Finance Program of BRAC and other Micro Finance Institutions.
- 3.To incorporate new tools and techniques in training modules required for analyzing financial performance of an institution more effectively.
- 4.To prepare monthly and yearly training plans.
- 5.Recruiting the official of BRAC Afghanistan on the basis of criteria developed by BRAC Human Resources Division.
- 6.To follow up and monitor training participants to assess there progress regarding field operation.
- 7. Monitor the implementation of BRAC HR policy at field level.
- 8. Corresponding with different divisions of BRAC & other organizations for training marketing.
- 9. Develop and maintain database for the Microfinance training program.
- 10. Any other duties as and when assigned by the supervisor in relation to the administrative and management related activities

Special accomplishment:

- a.Organized and conducted Exposure cum Training program on Micro Finance for Member of Parliaments, Board of Directors and Branch Managers of Tajikistan & Ghana.
- b.Conducted Training program on Micro Finance & Savings Management for the Senior Credit Officers and Managers of Central Bank of Ethiopia.
- c.Prepared training modules and other related papers as well as training on Office and Accounts Management for senior staff of Federation of NGO Bureau (FNB) in Bangladesh.

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pass Year
Post Graduate Diploma (PGD)	HRM	United International University & BSHRM	CGPA:3.22	2017
Master of Business Administration	Marketing	East West University	CGPA:3.2	2003
Bachelor of Business Administration	Finance	Darul Ihsan University	CGPA:2.74	2000
HSC	Science	Cantonment Public School and College, Bogra	First Div.	1994
SSC	Science	Cantonment Public School and College, Bogra	First Div.	1992

Technical Skill:

Data analytics, Advanced MS Excel, MS Word, MS PowerPoint

Training Summary:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
Domestic Enquiry & Labour Law 2006	Domestic Enquiry and labour law 2006	bdjobs.com	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2011	1 day
Occupational Safety and Health (OSH)	OSH & Industrial Visit	Jointly AOTS, Japan in co- operation with Bangladesh Employers` Federation	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2011	2 days
Effective interpersonal & Cross-Cultural Communication Practices	Cross-Cultural conflicts & Communication	AIT Extension, Asian Institute of Thailand	Thailand	Bangkok	2009	1 month
Financial Analysis for MFIs, CGAP	Income Statement and Balance Sheet analysis, Cost center, Ratio analysis	EDA Rural Systems Pvt Ltd, India	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2005	7 days
Training on Entitlements and Responsibilities	Rights and Responsibilities of employee	BRAC	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2004	2 days

Career and Application Information:

Looking For : Mid-Level Job Available For : Full Time

Expected Salary : As per company policy.

Preferred Job Category : Accounting/Finance, HR/Org. Development

Preferred Organization Types : Manufacturing (Light Engineering & Heavy Industry), Overseas

Companies

Specialization:

Fields of Specialization

- Labour Law
- Compliance
- HRIS
- Training
- Administration
- Distribution/ Supply Chain Management

Extra-Curricular Activities:

Playing Table tennis, Chess & watching English Movies. Got 6 in IELTS.

Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bengali	High	High	High
English	High	High	High
Sinhala	Low	Low	Low

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Late Sk. Z. Ferdous Mother's Name : Late Anwara Begum Date of Birth : October 20, 1977

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Bangladeshis

National Id No. : 2692848059216

Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : Comfort Housing Society, Bogura Sadar, Bogura Sadar, Bogura 5800

Current Location : Dhaka Blood Group : B+

Reference (s):

Reference: 01

Name : Md. Masud Sadik

Organization : National Board of Revenue

Designation : Member

Address : Segunbagicha, Dhaka.

Contact No. : As on request

Reference: 02

Dr. Enamul Hoque BRAC International Program Specialist Mohakhali, Dhaka. As on request